The Tucson Literary Club papers 1921-2011
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
The Tucson Literary Club papers 1921-2011
AZ 245
Tucson Literary Club
Chiefly typescripts of papers presented at monthly Club meetings. Also includes minutes of meetings, correspondence and member lists.
3.25 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None
Further accruals are anticipated.
Historical Note
The Literary Club was founded in 1921 by a group of University and professional men under the leadership of Dr. Frank C. Lockwood, professor of English, and dean of the College of Liberal Arts at University of Arizona. The first meeting took place on October 17, 1921. The Tucson Literary Club holds meetings from October to May. An original essay is presented at each meeting of Tucson Literary Club. The club continues to count a membership comprised of distinguished University faculty and staff as well as private citizens.
Arrangement
The collection is organized chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
Eight essays presented per season, not all are present. Some essays contain schedules and invitation cards. Papers by Laurence Muir, Nov. 1970, and Bernard Fontana, 1991, gave a history of the club. Presenters include James B. McCormick, Eugene Steinheimer, Evo DeConcinnini, Douglas D. Martin, Richard Harvill, Arthur N. Pack, Laurence Muir, Lawrence Clark Powell, John P. Schaefer, and Bernard Fontana. Also includes minutes of meetings, membership lists and correspondence.
Access Terms
University of Arizona--Faculty
Literature—Societies, etc. –Arizona—Tucson
Clubs—Arizona--Tucson
Container List
- Minutes of Meetings, October 1948-May 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes of Meetings, October 1960-March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes of Meetings, April 1976-October 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Essays, 1939-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Essays, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Essays, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Essays, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Essays, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Essays, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Essays, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Essays, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Essays, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Essays, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Essays, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Essays, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Essays, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Essays, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Essays, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Essays, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Essays, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Essays, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Essays, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Essays, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Essays, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Essays, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Essays, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Essays, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Essays, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Essays, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Essays, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Essays, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Essays, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Essays, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Essays, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Essays, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Essays, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Essays, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Essays, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Essays, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Essays, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Essays, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Essays, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Essays, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Essays, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Essays, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Essays, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Essays, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Essays, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Essays, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Essays, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Essays, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Essays, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Essays, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Essays, 2007-2008 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Essays, 2008-2009 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Essays, 2009-2010 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Essays, 2010-2011 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Minutes of Meetings, 2000-2007 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1921/1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Membership Lists, 1960-1991 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Host and Essayist Lists, 1921-1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Literary Club Meeting Invitations, 2000-2009 (Box 8, Folder 9)